Harsh Mishra

(323) 776-4684 | mishraharsh169@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/harsh-mishra-515624144/ | harshm16.github.io/

SUMMARY

Computer Science master's with 2 years of Industry experience as a Systems and Software Engineer at Hewlett Packard Enterprise. Experienced in automating infrastructure and deployment using CI/CD, Data Engineering, application of Machine learning algorithms and Data Visualization.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC)

Aug 2021-May 2023

Master of Science, Computer Science

GPA:3.85/4.0

Coursework: MS Thesis, Cloud Computing, Visual Data Science, Causal Inference, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

PES University, Bangalore

Aug 2015-May 2019

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

GPA:8.08/10

Coursework: Data Structures, Big Data, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning, Computer Network Security, Data Analytics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Python, C, R, Ansible, SQL

Familiar: Scala, Java, PowerShell, MATLAB, JavaScript, D3js

Tools/Software: Tableau, Docker, AWS (S3, Lambda, EMR, EBS, SageMaker, Kinesis), Hugging Face, Jira, Latex, Postman

LABORATORY WORK

Research Assistant, Computer Science Department, UIC

Sep 2021-Dec 2022

Technologies Used: Python, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Docker, Linux

- Trained Score based Generative Models using non-Gaussian noise. The paper was selected as a poster presentation at the MMLS 2023 conference. Preprint available on arxiv.org/pdf/2302.02336.pdf.
- Developed an algorithm to convert categorical labels/features to continuous labels, enabling the use of kernel methods for no de classification and other GNN tasks. Experiments on Event Stream and Pose Estimation data available on github.com/harshm16/GNN.
- Co-authored a paper on using optimization-based training methods in distributed Machine Learning settings to overcome byzantine worker problems. Preprint available on <u>arxiv.org/pdf/2302.05865.pdf</u>.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) - Bangalore, India

July 2019 – July 2021

- Systems and Software Engineer
 - Developed scripts to automate the deployment of MLOps as a Service offering. Used REST APIs to mimic deprecated PowerShell functions in Python and used Ansible for automated deployment.
 - Simulated cyber threat patterns using graph databases in Neo4j and wrote SQL queries to detect such patterns.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE) - Bangalore, India

Jan 2019-July 2019

Software Developer Intern

Developed and deployed a DataOps pipeline using open-source applications and wrote bash scripts to automate the CI/CD pipeline.

PROJECTS

ETL Pipeline, UIC

Oct 2021-Dec 2021

Technologies Used: Scala, D3.js, Kafka, AWS - EBS, Spark

Built and end to end Log Analysis pipeline. AWS EBS – continuously generate logs, Kafka – real time streaming, Hadoop Spark & MapReduce – data crunching, D3.js – dynamic visualization of results. – <u>Code</u>

Data Visualization, UIC 2022-Dec 2022

Technologies Used: D3.js, JS

Used all the stages of SDLC to come up with different ways to visualize amino acid data. The visualization allows the user to
dynamically interact with the 3D structures of the protein and shows visual representations of various other properties &
interrelations in the amino acid sequence. — <u>Code</u>

Causal Inference, UIC 2022-Dec 2022

Technologies Used: Python

Developed a causal analysis pipeline to identify factors that influenced public sentiments during the COVID-19 pandemic. The
experiments provide comparison between various structure finding algorithms used to find causal graphs and then utilizes
Bayesian Networks to find the conditional probabilities. – <u>Code</u>